What's going on, everybody? We are here in Cedar Park, Texas, just north of Austin. We're here for
our first speaking engagement. It's crazy to me thinking about a year ago what we were doing with
this channel, going around interviewing people in downtown Austin, and now we're here getting
our first speaking opportunity for the channel. How are we feeling today, man? We feel good,
man. We're prepared. We're coming to hopefully provide some value for the audience here. You
know, got a couple hundred people out there, so, you know, we're looking forward to just delivering
a good message. That way, people can benefit from it. Yeah, and later on the video, we're pretty
much going to be showing you guys what we talked about in our speech. Kind of our big thing today
is we're going to be talking about how people can unleash greatness through content creation, so
let's get it. All right, so my first question for you, Chris, is if you were to go back to when you
were in either high school or college, what is the best piece of advice that you would tell yourself?
I think that that person wouldn't necessarily have listened, but the reality is I would say
that taking the time to go to either college, university, I would tell them don't do that.
I instead would try to come up.
With somebody who is super influential and spend as much time with them as they possibly could.
Learn as much as they can so that at the time they actually enter the workforce,
they've learned real life skills. What industry did you decide to pursue a career?
Specifically got into K-12, so into the educational industry, really around consulting.
Consulting is a great business because it really takes and leverages your expertise,
which you can get. Like, you can acquire that expertise and then offer that to someone else.
That served me, not just in that industry, but as I've diversified,
into other industries. Now I know I can become an expert and then apply that same philosophy.
What advice would you give to someone wanting to start a business?
Be a disruptor. Trying to figure out like a better mousetrap.
What's that one thing you're gonna be able to do better than anyone else?
I would go at it from a perspective of how am I gonna disrupt an industry that have done it the same way
for the last 20, 30 years. What can we do leveraging technology or leveraging expertise
that'll completely disrupt? And even though that's probably one of the harder things to break into,
in my opinion, it is by far the largest impact you can make.
For younger people today, especially, whether it's a certain, you know, skill set or attribute,
you know, for someone to possess when they're going out into the real world,
how can someone become financially free in today's world?
Risk everything. I say this all the time. As an entrepreneur, I take a lot of risks financially.
People say, Chris, man, you have such a high risk tolerance. And I tell them yes and no.
I do with money and it's because I can make more tomorrow. But I have a low risk tolerance with time.
So I'm gonna go for it.
The worst thing to me on the planet is if I watch a Major League Baseball player strike out while looking.
Get that bat off your shoulder and swing away.
I guess the next thing I'll ask you is a fun one we've been asking people.
But if you had to start from zero and you had one year to make a million dollars and your life depended on it,
what would you do?
Real estate. Borrow other people's money, invest in a real estate, refinance, do it all over again.
What market would you look to invest in?
Any real estate that's available to you based on where you are.
So it could be commercial, could be residential, could be flipping homes.
But 86% of the wealth in the world is real estate.
And the rest of the wealth in this country is tied up in real estate.
That's where you want to go.
Look 40 miles outside of Austin.
Get outside the major metropolitan areas.
Get into areas where there's still a lot of growth potential.
It just hasn't been tapped yet.
My last question for you is, you know, for someone who did decide to go to college or coming out of school,
what is your best piece of advice to someone who is starting out in the real world today?
Make sure that whatever you're gonna do, you're all in.
Don't try things out.
You have to go for it and you have to give it time.
A year, two years, three years is not enough time.
You gotta be shooting for at least five years where you are all in.
So you're gonna have to give it time.
Sleep on someone's couch.
Don't go out to eat.
Put all the money you have away so that you can go for it in a way that most people will never have the discipline to do.
It's about 30 minutes before we're supposed to go on stage and speak at our first event.
How we feeling?
Feeling good, man.
Feeling good.
We prepared for this.
So, you know, just looking forward to going out there and again, just providing some value for people.
Oh no, are you nervous?
Sure.
I'm always a little nervous, you know, but hey, but we're built for this, man.
You know what I'm saying?
This is, I have never had an issue public speaking.
So I'm kind of looking forward to it a little bit.
Where'd you learn how to public speak?
Yeah.
And you know, I think that's enough.
You know, we actually really got into public speaking because of Boy Scouts and really just seeing our dad speak in front of thousands of people.
So yeah, we're looking forward to it, man.
Let's crush it.
30 minutes, baby.
Let's go.
I don't know.
I don't know how the boys are feeling right now, but I'm nervous myself.
Let's get this bread though.
Let's get this bread.
All right.
Yes, we are.
So we're the School of Hard Knocks and we actually have a question that we want to ask you guys kind of similar to what we do on our channel.
And so I'm going to start over here.
A question that we've been asking a lot of people recently is if you were to go back to when you were in high school, what would you do?
And give yourself a piece of advice.
What's the best piece of advice you tell your younger self?
You got it.
I'm going to break the rules or I'm going to bend them.
I'm going to give three.
Number one, I'm going to quote what Denzel Washington said, always put God first.
I did not have God in high school and college.
And I will tell you the minute I found in my life improved.
That was my North Compass.
I followed that.
And I just stopped worrying about other stuff.
The second thing is find someone that you can trust.
And I think that's the most important thing.
And I will tell you the minute I found in my life improved.
That was my North Compass.
I followed that.
And I just stopped worrying about other stuff.
The second thing is find someone that loves you for who you are.
I've been happily married three years now.
We have a beautiful 11 month deal to own.
Here it is, Chris.
I told you I was going to try not to cry.
When I found that, I just unleashed full potential.
I had someone that I could come home to and talk to.
I had someone in the peaks and the valleys that was there.
So that's my number one.
Number two, I'm going to give God first.
And I think that's the most important thing.
The third piece of advice is find a really good mentor.
And then find someone that you can pour into as well.
Don't think just because you're only 18, you can't find someone to pour into you absolutely
can.
Whether you're in college, whether you're in high school.
That platform should never stop.
So find a good mentor that will pour into you and then gently pouring it into yourself and
then know what the things you really need and I'm sure when you're at your lowest level
it's been able to make it your only way forward.
And then when that crochet comes together and you think, it's a small.
There are many of us that are there that want to be impacted.
And even if it's more of a 몇-page-per-page journey, each lesson you take is individual.
For sure.
Last, last, last.
and then find someone that you can pour into as well
because that's where the growing happens.
That's incredible.
Give it up for him.
All right, and then I have a different question for you.
With our interviews, we like to switch it up sometimes.
So I'm gonna catch you off guard
a little bit of a curve ball.
So my question for you is,
what's your best piece of advice
for young entrepreneurs in 2022?
A couple of things.
One, don't listen to the world
about what success looks like.
That's pretty big.
The second thing is, is do it in community.
And the third thing is,
is take time to enjoy life while you're doing it.
It's a lonely place.
Burnout is rampant.
And the only person that you're racing is yourself.
Incredible.
Give it up for him.
We can't let Mr. Mayor walk the hook here.
We gotta ask you,
kind of, we've been talking about this
a couple of times,
and I love your answer to this,
but how can someone scale a business
from five to six to seven, eight figures?
Yeah.
Scalability is always gonna come back
to how important you think you are in that organization.
I have, over the last five to six years,
really tried to become as unnecessary as possible.
And the way that I do that
is I try to bring out the greatness in everybody on my team.
Incredible.
Give it up for him.
Thank you.
All right, you guys are on.
Yes, sir.
Okay, everybody.
My name is Jack Dumoulin.
This is my brother, James Dumoulin,
and our good friend, Joshua Smith.
And we are the School of Hard Knocks.
So basically, we are a media channel
that just under a year grew to 1.1 million followers.
Our content is centered around going around
and asking people in different industries,
professionals, business owners, entrepreneurs,
basically trying to find financial literacy
and career mentorship, and then, you know,
we're trying to get people to give to young adults
through short-form content.
Wow.
And so, pretty much we've had the...
Thank you.
And so, pretty much we've had the pleasure
to interview the likes of Mark Cuban,
the former president of Nike,
the former CMO of T-Mobile,
the CEO of HopDotty, and many, many more.
And so today, we want to share with you
a piece of our journey to 1.1 million followers
by giving you three things that you can take
to unleash greatness through content creation,
and to build your brand.
But before we do that, we have to take you back
and kind of give you a little bit about how each of us
on our own journeys unleash greatness.
Absolutely.
So I'm James Dumlin, very blessed
and happy to be with you all today.
The three of us, it kind of starts out with,
we're all from the Washington, D.C. area.
And we met actually because we were
in the same Boy Scout troop.
Now, we all became Eagle Scouts together,
but ultimately, eagled out at different points.
And because there's an age difference,
Josh is 24, Jack's 22, and I'm 20,
so ultimately, when we eagled out, we were kind of at 20.
So ultimately, when we eagled out, we were kind of at 20.
So ultimately, when we eagled out, we were kind of at different points
in our lives.
Now, Josh decided to go to college, but at the same time,
him and a really good friend of his were growing
and scaling a digital marketing agency that kind of took off
and did really well.
So we came to a crossroads, decided, hey,
I'm putting a lot of time into school.
What if I put all that into my marketing agency in 10x that?
And that's what he did.
Left college, had a lot of success with his marketing agency.
Jack here had a dying, he had a crazy passion
for baseball statistics and sports statistics.
And he was a big fan of baseball statistics.
And he turned that into, he became a mastermind with analytics.
And at the end of high school, he ended up entering a competition
that was held by Microsoft and ,
which is pretty much through Microsoft Excel.
And he went all the way to the world competition and competed
in a world championship in Microsoft Excel.
And out of 2 million people,
he became the number one Microsoft Excel user
in the world.
It's crazy.
Listen, listen, you got to look it up.
I'm telling you.
Jack Dumoulin, Microsoft Excel, this is the number one user
of Microsoft Excel in the world.
I'm serious.
It's a real thing.
But through the, I'm serious.
It's one of the craziest stories ever.
Like, smartest kid I know, I promise you.
And, but through that, it opened up so many opportunities
and doors for him.
He decided to ultimately, like I said, we're from DC.
We moved out to, or he decided to move out to Austin
and go to UT.
But at the same time, he opened up his own, yeah,
welcome, yeah, he opened up his own,
kind of like tech consulting company
where he was building out, you know,
softwares and integrating that with Excel for companies
in different states.
And he also led to him having the opportunity.
He was pretty much mentored.
Everybody knows Bucky's, right?
So Bucky, one of the CEOs, one of the owners of Bucky's,
mentored him for about two years.
And so for myself personally, you know, I was behind them.
He was already out in Austin.
And it was around when the pandemic hit
and we really saw kind of the emergence
of various social media platforms,
and in particular TikTok.
And I grew really fascinated about how
there's all these people that are, you know,
finding their passion and they're able to monetize it
through just posting content around that.
I mean, I was seeing how the creator economy
was growing valuations in the next five years,
it's going to be over a hundred billion dollars.
And I was like, hey, this is something I could do.
I studied the algorithms and I was able to grow
my personal TikTok following to right around
a million followers in less than a year.
And, you know, through that, you know,
as I mentioned before, we all grew up in the DC area.
The thing about DC is it's a very strict
and structured city.
It's very centered around government jobs,
contracting, defense.
And I tell people, you want to work for Congress,
you want to go into politics, DC is the place to be.
But if you're entrepreneurial and have the desire
to start your own business, you got to get out of DC.
You got to get into a collaborative environment
like Austin, where everyone's looking to provide value
for one another.
So that kind of us having a similar mindset in that sense
is kind of what led to a further spark in our relationship.
So how it all kind of came together is late 2020,
we met at a mutual friend's house and really
reconnected over a couple of years.
It's been years since we've seen each other.
And we realized we had a lot of similar interests and goals,
and we knew we wanted to work on something,
but we weren't sure what it was going to be.
So the only problem with that is that Jack and James
were about to move to Texas permanently a week later.
So what we had to do is I was thinking of ideas
of what we could do in a week or shortly after they moved
to Texas, I called them and I pitched them on starting
an e-sports and gaming channel and they agreed.
And we started that and we grew it to about 10,000 followers
after a couple of months.
And even though the channel was going well,
it wasn't something we were all passionate about.
So we decided to pivot.
And so what we decided to do is we all have a passion
and interest in business.
And we wanted to share some of the lessons that we've learned
along the way from our mentors and just share ideas
with other people.
But we soon realized that people don't want to learn
about business from some young 20 year old guys,
no one knows who they are.
So we had to make another change.
And that's when we started to do street interviews.
And we noticed after the first interview that we posted,
our channel really started to get some really good traction.
And so then we saw the greater vision for the company
and we wanted to seek out the best of the best.
And that's how we've been able to get interviews
like Mark Cuban, CEO of HopDotty and others.
And that's where we were really just able to grow the channel
and it really took off after that point
once we started doing the interviews.
100%.
And so looking back at our journey of how that kind of
brought us together to start the School of Hard Knocks,
which is the name of our channel,
we were able to comprise some of the lessons
that we actually learned from content creation.
And we want to bring that to you today.
And so we have three major things.
The first being is that when you want to create content
and grow your brand, you need to find your why.
And although find your why might sound kind of cliche,
like, oh, find your why, what even is that?
The reason why I say it's important is because
if you don't have a why, if you don't have a mission
for why you want to create content or grow your brand,
there's going to, you're going to run into a lot of people
who are going to run into two things as a content creator
that stumbles every kind of creator early on
in their journey.
The first of that being is getting discouraged
with views, likes, followers, the numbers.
You get discouraged if you post a video
and it just doesn't do well.
James actually gave me great advice on this
while he was growing his brand.
Yeah, and this is something that I really tried to instill
kind of in our mindset when we were going forward
with Hard Knocks is that when you're starting out,
when you're getting out of your comfort zone,
you may not be used to putting yourself behind a camera,
putting that content out to where potentially
hundreds and thousands of people can see it.
And, you know, therefore, you really just have to,
like he said, you can't get discouraged.
You can't care about what other people think.
You just have to go for it.
You know, if you have the vision,
if you see the potential in it, just send it, go for it.
And I'm telling you, as long as you remember
why you're doing it and the greater purpose,
it's going to pay off.
Exactly.
So the first thing being you have to overcome
being discouraged about views.
You could put one piece of content,
three pieces of content, five pieces of content.
It doesn't do well.
If you ultimately decide to give up and quit
just because not enough people saw your content at first,
then you're never going to be able to start a channel.
For us in particular, for the School of Hard Knocks,
when we started doing business content,
we had put out 200 pieces of content on our Instagram
for over a month and only had about 35,
40 followers to begin with.
That's not a lot of support for putting out 200 pieces
of good quality content.
And so if you don't have your why, you're just going to quit.
The second being is you can't be afraid of failure.
You can't be afraid of people judging you
when you get on camera.
You can't be afraid of what they think of you
because if you ultimately have your mission, your why,
and why you're making this great content for people,
then that stuff's not going to matter to you.
For us in particular, when we went up and interviewed
Mark Cuban, we actually saw him at South by Southwest
just after he gave a talk on the street.
If we didn't have the courage to go up and ask him and say,
hey, we run this channel.
We want to give back to the younger generation.
Could we ask you a question?
What advice would you tell your younger self?
If we were so afraid of getting rejected by him,
then that video never would have gotten posted,
never would have gotten the millions of views that it did
and the people that it impacted.
When we saw the impact
of videos like our interview with Mark Cuban,
we quickly realized that our impact spread
beyond the United States.
Over 50% of our 1.1 million following is outside of the US.
And we even had people reaching out to us and saying,
hey, I just started my dream business on the side of my job
because of a video that we saw.
We even saw that people were starting to save money.
And so that ultimately is why you need to find your why.
For us, we wanted to change the way that financial literacy
and career mentorship is taught in schools.
We also had great mentors around us.
And we noticed that a lot of our peers didn't.
And we wanted to bring that through our content.
But ultimately, if things aren't going well,
you can always change it up.
Just like in business, in content is exactly the same.
Is if things aren't working out, you need to pivot.
And so in our business, we had to pivot twice.
Like I said, we started as an e-sports company,
switched to business.
People don't want to learn business from young guys,
switched it again to interviews.
And this is where things finally started to click.
And if things aren't working out for you,
you're posting consistently and it's not working,
here are some things that I would recommend
that you can consider doing.
The first thing would be change up the delivery
of the actual content.
Change up your storytelling and how you're approaching
the content and the viewer.
And that's the number one thing,
is you actually have to focus on the viewer.
And the second thing, also to add onto that, is the editing.
The second thing you should consider doing
is changing your niche or topic that you're talking about.
Let's say you're talking about business overall.
Maybe you need to go a little bit deeper
and go into a sector like marketing.
And then you can go a little bit deeper
and talk about that.
The third thing I would recommend doing
is if things still aren't working out,
is model someone that is successful
within what you want to do and model after them.
But ultimately, the most important thing you can do
is be consistent.
Hands down, for us in particular,
the absolute most valuable trait and thing
that we brought into our company and through our content
is just being consistent.
Early on, you don't have a lot of followers,
you don't have a huge base.
It's all about volume early on.
You've got to be putting out numerous pieces of content.
I love to give this analogy whenever I'm talking to people.
You have person A and you have person B.
Person A is getting into content,
he's going through the motions, he's like,
hey, I'm putting out a couple posts a week.
And then you have person B.
Person B, he's like, hey, this is my structured
posting schedule, I'm gonna be putting up
three to four pieces of content a day.
When you look at the end of a week,
that person's putting up 20 to 30 pieces of content
as opposed to the other person
just going through the motions.
That person who's putting up all that content
is gonna beat that person 10 times out of 10 times.
Yeah, I even saw this with James' personal journey
when he started posting content.
Every single day, he was posting three, four times a day
for 60 days straight.
People might not think making TikToks and videos
is difficult.
Well, let me tell you, trying to make three or four videos
a day with everything that you have going on
for 60 days straight is difficult.
And we ultimately saw that him, in that one month,
that he was so consistent, he grew his personal following
over half a million people within one month.
Yeah, and so again, incorporating that
and the biggest thing is,
especially when it comes down to the algorithms,
is that these social media algorithms,
they will reward you for being consistent.
They are built off of keeping people on their apps.
If you can post consistently,
get people to engage with your content,
these algorithms will reward you.
You will grow, you'll build your base of followers,
and you'll scale your business.
You'll start to see your views take off.
So once again, if there's any one big lesson
that I could give to you that's led to our success,
my success in my personal content journey, it's that,
you have to be consistent.
Absolutely, and so finding your why for those times
when you get discouraged or afraid of failure,
pivoting when things aren't working out
so you can find the piece of content that works,
and being consistent, those three are the ultimate things
that we believe will bring you success as a content creator.
And so with that, we hope that you guys are able
to now go out and unleash greatness through your content
and growing your brand.
We are the School of Hard Knocks.
Thank you guys very much.
Thank you.
I'm gonna take a Be Real.
Have you guys heard of Be Real?
You guys heard of Be Real?
Awesome, awesome.
Thank you guys so much, yeah.
Thank you.
God bless you guys.
Come on, let's go.
We need to go back to you.
I'll try to talk about, hey,
this is my man Mariana right here.
We just met up after the talk.
Yeah, so what'd you think?
Yeah, absolutely.
So I thought, yeah, we're very well spoken.
I really liked it a lot.
You know, it took a lot of the crowd by surprise
to see how young y'all are
and how y'all have found success at such an early age.
I had to come up here and say what's up
because, you know, hook them.
You know, I went to UT, just graduated,
and I just wanted to hear a little bit more
and see, you know, put a face to their brand
and something that I just wanted to connect with them.
If I have them there,
why not take the opportunity, right?
They talked about having courage
and walking up to Mark Cuban in their speech up there,
and what's the worst they could have said?
No, right?
I did come up here and we connected.
We got each other's numbers.
Very personable people.
I really, really appreciate them for taking the time.
We're gonna go get some coffee later sometime
and talk about, you know, what it is they're doing,
what it is that I'm doing, you know, bounce off ideas.
And I just really appreciated the content
that they put out there.
They really know how to market to their audience.
They know their niche.
They know what they're doing and they have their why,
and I think that's the most important part.
And that's something that they really hit and talked about
is just how their why is so important to them
and what keeps them being consistent.
And I think that's important, especially for our generation.
You know, sometimes we could be looked down upon,
especially with like social media
and how it's all over the place.
So, you know, make sure y'all have y'all's why too,
and keep tuning in.
And I know they have a lot of things coming in the future.
So thank y'all so much.
Mariana, great to meet you.
It was a pleasure.
All right guys, that was our first speaking engagement
as the Hard Knocks team.
Hope you guys enjoyed it.
I mean, I had a great time.
Dude, that was an incredible experience.
I was honestly so nervous right before we got on stage.
But once we got out there, man, it just, like Chris said,
or Zach said, you just black out.
You just get in the zone and you do it.
So it was an amazing experience.
And James, what was your final thoughts?
Man, just super, super happy to, like they were saying,
have this experience.
And just blessed to be able to come out here,
share some of our value for people.
And like he said, man, it was a little nervous at first.
But once we got in the zone, we feel
like we clicked with the audience.
So we really enjoyed that.
If you guys enjoyed our speech or you enjoyed this video,
make sure to leave a like and subscribe
to the channel.
We got a lot of great content coming.
And we hope to see you at our next speaking engagement.